an instinct like that might actually have consequences, because the first thing that I discovered is that it's not just me. In 2007, the Washington Post reported that the United States military was testing this robot that defused land mines. And the way it worked was it was shaped like a stick insect and it would walk around a minefield on its legs, and every time it stepped on a mine, one of the legs would blow up, and it would continue on the other legs to blow up more mines. And the colonel who was in charge of this testing exercise ends up calling it off, because, he says, it's too inhumane to watch this damaged robot drag itself along the minefield. Now, what would cause a hardened military officer and someone like myself to have this response to robots? Well, of course, we're primed by science fiction and pop culture to really want to personify these things, but it goes a little bit deeper than that. It turns out that we're biologically hardwired to project intent and life onto any movement in our physical space that seems autonomous to us. So people will treat all sorts of robots like they're alive. These bomb-disposal units get names. They get medals of honor. They've had funerals for them with gun salutes. And research shows that we do this even with very simple household robots, like the Roomba vacuum cleaner. (Laughter) It's just a disc that roams around your floor to clean it, but just the fact it's moving around on its own will cause people to name the Roomba and feel bad for the Roomba when it gets stuck under the couch. (Laughter) And we can design robots specifically to evoke this response, using eyes and faces or movements that people automatically, subconsciously associate with states of mind. And there's an entire body of research called human-robot interaction that really shows how well this works. So for example, researchers at Stanford University found out that it makes people really uncomfortable when you ask them to touch a robot's private parts. (Laughter) So from this, but from many other studies, we know, we know that people respond to the cues given to them by these lifelike machines, even if they know that they're not real. Now, we're headed towards a world where robots are everywhere. Robotic technology is moving out from behind factory walls. It's entering workplaces, households. And as these machines that can sense and make autonomous decisions and learn enter into these shared spaces, I think that maybe the best analogy we have for this is our relationship with animals. Thousands of years ago, we started to domesticate animals, and we trained them for work and weaponry and companionship. And throughout history, we've treated some animals like tools or like products, and other animals, we've treated with kindness and we've given a place in society as our companions. I think it's plausible we might start to integrate robots in similar ways. And sure, animals are alive. Robots are not. And I can tell you, from working with roboticists, that we're pretty far away from developing robots that can feel anything. But we feel for them, and that matters, because if we're trying to integrate robots into these shared spaces, we need to understand that people will treat them differently than other devices, and that in some cases, for example, the case of a soldier who becomes emotionally attached to the robot that they work with, that can be anything from inefficient to dangerous. But in other cases, it can actually be useful to foster this emotional connection to robots. We're already seeing some great use cases, for example, robots working with autistic children to engage them in ways that we haven't seen previously, or robots working with teachers to engage kids in learning with new results. And it's not just for kids. Early studies show that robots can help doctors and patients in health care settings. This is the PARO baby seal robot. It's used in nursing homes and with dementia patients. It's been around for a while. And I remember, years ago, being at a party and telling someone about this robot, and her response was, "Oh my gosh. That's horrible. I can't believe we're giving people robots instead of human care." And this is a really common response, and I think it's absolutely correct, because that would be terrible. But in this case, it's not what this robot replaces. What this robot replaces is animal therapy in contexts where we can't use real animals but we can use robots, because people will consistently treat them more like an animal than a device. Acknowledging this emotional connection to robots can also help us anticipate challenges as these devices move into more intimate areas of people's lives. For example, is it OK if your child's teddy bear robot records private conversations? Is it OK if your sex robot has compelling in-app purchases? (Laughter) Because robots plus capitalism equals questions around consumer protection and privacy. And those aren't the only reasons that our behavior around these machines could matter. A few years after that first initial experience I had with this baby dinosaur robot, I did a workshop with my friend Hannes Gassert. And we took five of these baby dinosaur robots and we gave them to five teams of people. And we had them name them and play with them and interact with them for about an hour. And then we unveiled a hammer and a hatchet and we told them to torture and kill the robots. (Laughter) And this turned out to be a little more dramatic than we expected it to be, because none of the participants would even so much as strike these baby dinosaur robots, so we had to improvise a little, and at some point, we said, "OK, you can save your team's robot if you destroy another team's robot." (Laughter) And even that didn't work. They couldn't do it. So finally, we said, "We're going to destroy all of the robots unless someone takes a hatchet to one of them." And this guy stood up, and he took the hatchet, and the whole room winced as he brought the hatchet down on the robot's neck, and there was this half-joking, half-serious moment of silence in the room for this fallen robot. (Laughter) So that was a really interesting experience. Now, it wasn't a controlled study, obviously, but it did lead to some later research that I did at MIT with Palash Nandy and Cynthia Breazeal, where we had people come into the lab and smash these HEXBUGs that move around in a really lifelike way, like insects. So instead of choosing something cute that people are drawn to, we chose something more basic, and what we found was that high-empathy people would hesitate more to hit the HEXBUGS. Now this is just a little study, but it's part of a larger body of research that is starting to indicate that there may be a connection between people's tendencies for empathy and their behavior around robots. But my question for the coming era of human-robot interaction is not: "Do we empathize with robots?" It's: "Can robots change people's empathy?" Is there reason to, for example, prevent your child from kicking a robotic dog, not just out of respect for property, but because the child might be more likely to kick a real dog? And again, it's not just kids. This is the violent video games question, but it's on a completely new level because of this visceral physicality that we respond more intensely to than to images on a screen. When we behave violently towards robots, specifically robots that are designed to mimic life, is that a healthy outlet for violent behavior or is that training our cruelty muscles? We don't know ... But the answer to this question has the potential to impact human behavior, it has the potential to impact social norms, it has the potential to inspire rules around what we can and can't do with certain robots, similar to our animal cruelty laws. Because even if robots can't feel, our behavior towards them might matter for us. And regardless of whether we end up changing our rules, robots might be able to help us come to a new understanding of ourselves. Most of what I've learned over the past 10 years has not been about technology at all. It's been about human psychology and empathy and how we relate to others. Because when a child is kind to a Roomba, when a soldier tries to save a robot on the battlefield, or when a group of people refuses to harm a robotic baby dinosaur, those robots aren't just motors and gears and algorithms. They're reflections of our own humanity. Thank you. (Applause)
un instinto así podría tener consecuencias, porque lo primero que descubrí es que no soy solo yo. En 2007 el Washington Post informó que los militares de EE. UU. estaban probando el robot que desactivaba minas terrestres. Y funcionaba con la forma de un insecto palo, caminando sobre sus piernas alrededor de un campo minado y cada vez que pisaba una mina, una de las piernas explotaba, y seguía sobre las restantes piernas para hacer explotar más minas. Y el coronel a cargo de este ejercicio de prueba terminó suspendiendo, porque decía que era demasiado inhumano ver a ese robot dañado arrastrarse por el campo minado. Y ¿qué causaría que un oficial militar endurecido y alguien como yo tuviéramos esa reacción a los robots? Por supuesto, estamos preparados por la ciencia ficción y la cultura pop a querer de verdad personificar estas cosas, pero esto es un poco más profundo que eso. Resulta que estamos biológicamente programados para proyectar intencionalidad y vida a cualquier movimiento en nuestro espacio físico que nos parezca autónomo. Así que la gente tratará todo tipo de robots como si estuvieran vivos. Estas unidades de eliminación de bombas obtienen nombres. Obtienen medallas de honor. Les han homenajeado con funerales con salvas. Y la investigación muestra que lo hacemos incluso con robots domésticos muy simples, como la aspiradora Roomba. (Risas) Es solo un disco que vaga por el piso para limpiarlo, pero el hecho de que se está moviendo de forma autónoma hará que la gente le denomine el Roomba y se sienta mal por el Roomba cuando se atasca debajo del sofá. (Risas) Y podemos diseñar concretamente robots para evocar esta respuesta, usando ojos y caras o movimientos. para que la gente automáticamente y subconscientemente lo asocie con estados de ánimo. Y hay todo un cuerpo de investigación denominado interacción humano-robot que muestra realmente lo bien que funciona esto. Por ejemplo, los investigadores de la Universidad de Stanford descubrieron que la gente se siente realmente incómoda cuando se les pide tocar las partes íntimas de un robot. (Risas) A partir de esto y a partir de muchos otros estudios, sabemos que las personas responden a las señales que reciben a través de estas máquinas realistas, incluso sabiendo que no son reales. Nos dirigimos hacia un mundo donde los robots estarán en todas partes. La robótica se está moviendo desde detrás de las paredes de la fábrica. Está entrando a los lugares de trabajo, a los hogares. Y como esas máquinas pueden percibir y tomar decisiones autónomas y aprender, entran en estos espacios compartidos. Creo que tal vez la mejor analogía que tenemos para esto es nuestra relación con los animales. Hace miles de años comenzamos a domesticar animales, y los entrenamos para el trabajo, la guerra y la compañía. Y a lo largo de la historia hemos tratado a algunos animales como herramientas o productos similares. y a otros animales los hemos tratado con amabilidad. Y les hemos dado un lugar en la sociedad como nuestros compañeros. Creo entonces plausible comenzar a integrar robots de manera similar. Y claro, los animales están vivos. Los robots no. Y les puedo decir, por mi trabajo en robótica. que estamos bastante lejos de desarrollar robots que puedan sentir. Pero sentimos por ellos, y eso importa, Porque si intentamos integrar robots en estos espacios compartidos, hay que entender que las personas los tratarán de manera diferente a otros dispositivos, y que, en algunos casos, por ejemplo, el caso de un soldado que se une emocionalmente al robot con el que trabaja, puede ser desde ineficiente hasta peligroso. Pero en otros casos, en realidad, puede ser útil fomentar esta conexión emocional con los robots. Ya estamos viendo algunos buenos casos de uso, Por ejemplo, robots que trabajan con niños autistas. para involucrarlos en formas que no se han visto antes o robots que trabajan con maestros para involucrar a los niños en el aprendizaje con nuevos resultados. Y no solo para niños. Los primeros estudios muestran que los robots pueden ayudar a médicos y pacientes en entornos sanitarios. Este es el robot de foca bebé PARO. Se utilizan en hogares de ancianos y con pacientes con demencia y ya se aplican hace algún tiempo. Y recuerdo, hace años estar en una fiesta contándole a alguien sobre este robot, y su respuesta fue, "Oh Dios mío. Esto es horrible. No puedo creer estar dando a las personas robots en vez de cuidado humano". Y esta es una respuesta muy común, y creo que es absolutamente correcto, porque eso sería terrible. Pero en este caso, no es lo que reemplaza este robot. Lo que este robot reemplaza es la terapia animal. En contextos donde no podemos usar animales reales, podemos usar robots, porque la gente los tratará de forma más parecida a un animal que a un dispositivo. Reconocer esta conexión emocional con los robots también nos puede ayudar a anticipar desafíos, porque estos dispositivos se mueven hacia áreas más íntimas de la vida de las personas. Por ejemplo, ¿está bien si el robot de oso de peluche de su hijo graba conversaciones privadas? ¿Está bien si su robot sexual tiene compras atractivas dentro de la app? (Risas) Porque los robots más capitalismo es igual a preguntas sobre la protección del consumidor y la privacidad. Y esas no son las únicas razones para que nuestro comportamiento relacionado con estas máquinas pueda ser relevante. Unos años antes de esa primera experiencia inicial con este robot dinosaurio bebé, hice un taller con mi amigo Hannes Gassert. Y tomamos cinco de estos robots bebé dinosaurio y se los dimos a cinco equipos de personas. Y les pedimos que los nombraran y jugaran e interactuaran con ellos durante aproximadamente una hora. Y luego les dimos un martillo y un hacha y les dijimos que torturaran y mataran a los robots. (Risas) Y esto resultó ser un poco más dramático. de lo que esperábamos, porque ninguno de los participantes lo hizo eso a estos robots dinosaurios bebé, así que tuvimos que improvisar un poco, y en un momento dijimos, "Bien, pueden salvar el robot de su equipo si destruyen el robot de otro equipo". (Risas) E incluso eso no funcionó. No querían hacerlo. Así que finalmente, dijimos, "Vamos a destruir todos los robots a no ser que alguien destruya con un hacha uno de ellos". Y un tipo se puso de pie y tomó el hacha, y toda la habitación se estremeció cuando dio un hachazo en el cuello del robot, y hubo un momento de silencio medio jocoso, medio serio en la habitación por este robot muerto. (Risas) Fue una experiencia realmente interesante. No era un estudio controlado, obviamente, pero condujo a una investigación posterior que hice en el MIT con Palash Nandy y Cynthia Breazeal, donde hubo personas que vinieron al laboratorio y aplastaron a estos HEXBUGs que se mueven de manera muy realista, como los insectos. Así que en lugar de elegir algo lindo que atrae a la gente, elegimos algo más básico. Y lo que descubrimos fue que las personas de alta empatía dudaban más en golpear a los HEXBUGS. Esto es solo un pequeño estudio, pero es parte de un gran cuerpo de investigación. Eso está empezando a indicar que puede haber una conexión entre las tendencias de empatía de las personas y su comportamiento en torno a los robots. Pero mi pregunta para la era venidera de la interacción humano-robot no es: "¿Simpatizamos con los robots?", sino: "¿Pueden los robots cambiar la empatía de las personas?". ¿Hay alguna razón para, por ejemplo, evitar que su hijo patee a un perro robótico, no solo por respeto a la propiedad, sino porque el niño podría ser más propenso a patear a un perro de verdad? Y de nuevo, no son solo niños. Esta es la pregunta sobre los videojuegos violentos, pero a un nivel completamente nuevo, debido a esta fisicalidad visceral a la que respondemos más intensamente que a las imágenes en una pantalla. Cuando nos comportamos violentamente hacia los robots, concretamente robots diseñados para imitar la vida, ¿es esta una salida saludable para el comportamiento violento o significa entrenar nuestros músculos para la crueldad? Nosotros no lo sabemos. Sin embargo, la respuesta a esta pregunta tiene el potencial de impactar el comportamiento humano, tiene el potencial de impactar normas sociales, tiene el potencial de inspirar reglas sobre lo que podemos y no podemos hacer con ciertos robots, similar a nuestras leyes de crueldad animal. Porque incluso si los robots no pueden sentir, nuestro comportamiento hacia ellos puede ser importante para nosotros. Y sin importar si terminamos cambiando nuestras reglas, los robots podrían ayudarnos a llegar a una nueva comprensión de nosotros mismos. La mayor parte de lo que he aprendido en los últimos 10 años, no es tecnología en absoluto, sino psicología humana empatía y cómo nos relacionamos con los demás. Porque cuando un niño es amable con un Roomba, cuando un soldado trata de salvar a un robot en el campo de batalla, o cuando un grupo de personas se niega a dañar a un bebé dinosaurio robótico, esos robots no son solo motores, engranajes y algoritmos, son reflejos de nuestra propia humanidad. Gracias. (Aplausos)